In this segment we're going to build the clew patch for this Omega Fourteen Jib sail.
Our clew patch dimensions are going to be about 27" tall and taper down to about 18" on the foot edge.
It'll be a nice fanned out radial pattern.
So, all of the load in the sail will be, or the load in the clew will be transferred onto these panels.
The idea with the radial patch is that all the load follows the thread line into the sail.
Before you stick them together you can just lay them out like that and you'll get a really good idea of what kind of clew patch you're going to need.
Again, I'm trimming the clew patch here to make sure the grommet falls in the thickest part where all the layers meet.
You can't use too much sticky tape, so keep taping, lots and lots of tape.
There we go, we have a nice wall fitting clew patch.
I'm going to go ahead and tape the backside of it.
Like the other, peel the tape off.
The clew patch has to go inside of the lines.
I lined up the leach edge.
I'll stick the patch down and now trim along our foot line.
There is our clew patch.
You can see the patch doesn't go all the way to the edge of the sail because we're going to need to fold this edge over; as well as fold the foot edge over.
We're going to go on to sewing the patches down.
Right now I'm doing the tack patch.
Kind of the order you want to do is; the clew patch is obviously going to be the largest, the head patch will be the second largest and the tack patch is well, pretty tiny.
There is the tack patch.